Liam McLeod Curriculum Vitae

Liam McLeod

(+44)7936016617, L.McLeod95@gmail.com

me.liammcleod.co.uk

491 Bexhill Road, St Leonards-on-Sea, East Sussex, TN38 8AT

Key Skills:

IT literate -Excellent knowledge of Microsoft Office and other specialist software suites, applications and programming: Including Photoshop, Illustrator, Visual Studio, Eclipse, PHPStorm. Web Development in HTML (& Jade), CSS (& SCSS), PHP (& Laravel) and JS (& Node, JQuery, VueJS) in their most recent iterations using a variety of tools, and finally application development, specifically in VB.NET, Java and JS.

Polite, well-spoken and literate.

Knowledge in a wide range of subjects, mainly within computer science:

- Computer systems and servers,

- Networking,

- Web development (HTML, CSS, JS, PHP),

 Database design, MySQL, SQL Server and PostgreSQL,

- NodeJS, Express and Laravel,

Designing and manipulating computer graphics,

- System and network security,

Multiple projects in VueJS

- Familiar with GIT and version control.

Personal Skills:

- Good communication

Flexible

- Problem Solving

- Numeracy, Literacy and IT Skills

Independent (but adaptable)

- Dedicated

Education and Training

2011-2015:

Bexhill 6th Form College, Penland Road, Bexhill-on-Sea, TN40 2JG, United Kingdom

2011-12: Guitar Enrichment2013-14: Volunteer Enrichment2011-13 Level 3 Specialist National2013-15: AS Computing (B), A-Level

Diploma in IT (DMM), Psychology (D)

2006-2011:

The Grove, Darwell Close, St Leonards-on-Sea, East Sussex, TN38 9JP

- GCSEs: Maths (C), English (C), Catering (C), English Literature (B), Sciences: Chemistry: (B,) Physics: (B), Biology: (B) and Geography (C).
- BTECs: Level 2 Information Technology (Distinction) and Physical Education (Merit).

Employment and Experience

2010:

The Grove, Darwell Close, St Leonards-on-Sea, East Sussex, TN38 9JP

Teaching Assistant for Music, English and Sciences (Work Experience)

2013-2016:

Bexhill 6th Form College, Penland Road, Bexhill-on-Sea, TN40 2JG, United Kingdom

- Volunteer Enrichment (2013-14)
- Full-time volunteer in IT Faculty (2015-16) Reporting to Gary Newport

Liam McLeod Curriculum Vitae

2016-Current:

Freelance Web Developer

- PMJ Groundworks (Business Site PHP5.5)
- Personal (Personal Site HTML-CSS)
- <u>Examplar</u> (Exam Paper Search Tool On Hold NodeJS / VueJS Frontend)
- <u>Credence</u> (Academic Confidence Tool In development, full time Laravel / VueJS Frontend)

Personal Statement:

Leisure Interests: My leisure and recreational interests include web development, music, politics and sciences. I enjoy a range of other activities predominantly learning, reading and live music performances both attending and playing in a band, which I have released an EP while in. For the most part this includes making web applications for learning new technologies, playing guitar. It is for this reason I decided to take my education further and study areas of computer science further at university while I volunteered in the IT Faculty of Bexhill College, though the former did not work out. To back this further I have previously had work experience at the Grove College as a Teaching Assistant where I assisted in the preparation, teaching and covering of lessons spanning English, the sciences, religious education and music. I enjoy learning that is why I decided to make the most of my opportunities at Bexhill College where I have studied four subjects and voluntarily assisted in the maintenance of the IT department resources resulting in me, being invited back to assist in the teaching, generation of resources and running of student support sessions alongside general department maintenance. Due to much of my positive experience within education, I have consistently maintained a hunger and drive to learn new things especially within the fields of IT and the sciences, which I consider an important aspect of life and development both personally and collectively. I am hoping that at some point in the future I may re-join the world of academia to develop myself further.

Personal Statement: I am a polite, well-mannered person who is keen to learn new skills and adapt to new environments. I am sociable, hardworking and determined with my work. My ideal employment would be to work within an IT based environment. However, I am happy to adapt to any environment required. I am aspirational and keen to work my way up within a business. Throughout my entire academic career I have strived to maintain a high-level of quality in my work, punctuality and my attendance, which has consistently been 100% up until my final year in college, and throughout my volunteering career, something I know can only be an asset to any employer.

References

(Available upon request)